A Guide to the Papers of Archie L. Boswell 1958-1961
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Archie L. Boswell
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 59
The collection consists of two Hollinger boxes - one on each case.
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Norfolk attorney Archie L. Boswell acted as attorney for the defendants in the cases of James vs. Duckworth and James vs. Almond, the two cases to reopen the Norfolk schools closed to avoid integration as part of Virginia's Massive Resistance. This collection consists of his papers relating to those two cases, and includes various legal materials, correspondence, notes, background research, and other items.
Contents List
- SERIES I: JAMES VS. DUCKWORTH
  - Correspondence January 1959-June 1959 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence July 1959 - October 1959 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence November 1959 - August 1961 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brief for Appellants (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reply and Appendix to Brief (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appeal (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Petition for a Writ of Certiorari (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Financial (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notes (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Norfolk City Council (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
- SERIES II: JAMES VS. ALMOND
  - Correspondence October 1958-December 1958 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence January 1959-June 1960 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers, I (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers, II (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Trial Proceedings (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Plaintiff's Trial Memorandum (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brief on Behalf of Defendants (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Brief on Behalf of Petitioner, Harrison vs. Day (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Background Information (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Norfolk City Ordinances (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notes, Lists (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Printed Materials (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Duplicate Material (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 13)